

Ph.D. STUDENT IN COMPUTER SCIENCE | MACHINE LEARNING | MOBILE HEALTH | EMBEDDED SYSTEMS

🛮 (+1) 509-339-5866 | 🜌 ramesh.sah@wsu.edu | 🏶 www.rameshkrsah.github.io | 🖸 rameshKrSah | 🛅 rameshkrsah | 🎓 Ramesh Kumar Sah

"We are what we repeatedly do. Excellence, therefore, is not an act but a habit."

Summary _____

I am a Computer Science Ph.D. student at Washington State University researching novel machine learning algorithms and optimization processes using wearable sensor systems. I am interested in practical applications of machine learning and sensor systems to real-world problems.

Transferable Skills

- Efficient at analyzing problems and thinking through for possible solutions
- Quick learner with focus on both research methodology and product innovations
- Excellent work ethics and time management skills

Skills_

Programming Languages Python, C, C++, Bash

Framework & Libraries PyTorch, TensorFlow, Keras, Scikit-Learn

Software Engineering Tools Git, vim, ₺\\\
EX

Databases MySQL

Hardware Platform ARM-Cortex M, ESP8266, ESP32

Experience _____

Proctor & Gamble, Smart Products

Mason, OH.

MACHINE LEARNING INTERN

Jun. 2021 - Aug. 2021

- Researched Binarized Neural Networks (BNNs) and consolidated the findings by developing a library to train a Binary Convolutional neural network
 from scratch.
- Developed the inference pipeline to accelerate and deploy binary models for ARM-32, ARM-64 embedded platforms, and Android devices.
- · Trained and deployed 1D Binary CNN model for human activity classification using inertial sensor data
- Trained Binary image classification and object detection models using IMAGENet dataset and deployed the trained model on Raspberry PI and Android devices. Binary models did not suffer from performance drop but at the same time showed significant improvements in terms of memory and computation speed.

Rewire Neuro Remote

Machine Learning Consultant

Aug. 2021 - Current

• Helping medical scientists to develop machine learning models to determine the ototoxicity of chemical compounds.

Washington State University

GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Pullman, WA.

May. 2019 - Aug. 2021

- Quantified, measured, and detected stress in real-time in alcohol-addicted individuals using machine learning algorithms and sensor systems. We aim to build a mobile health system that can detect stress and provide interventions such as music therapy, games, and inspirational texts to prevent alcohol-dependent people from relapsing.
- Developing an Android app to collect inertial, positional, bio-markers, and image data for a human-in-the-loop activity monitoring system to learn activity and behavioral patterns in an individual. Wrote the firmware for the camera module based on the ESP-32 system-on-chip.
- Investigated the effects of adversarial examples in wearable sensor systems used in health care. We showed how an adversary can craft adversarial examples and fool the underlying machine learning models.
- Investigated the transferability of adversarial examples in wearable sensor systems from four novel different perspectives: 1) transferability between models, 2) transferability between subjects, 3) transferability across sensor body locations, and 4) transferability between datasets.

Washington State University

Pullman, WA.

Graduate Teaching Assistant

Aug. 2018 - May. 2019

- Helped students with their problems and graded homework and exams in several Computer Science courses.
- Gave lectures in a class with 150 students.
- Courses: Introduction to Machine Learning, Data Structures and Algorithms, Software Development, Embedded Systems, and Computer Architecture

Real Time Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

Patan, Nepal

FIRMWARE ENGINEER Dec. 2016 - Aug. 2018

- Wrote efficient and resilient C/C++ code for products ranging from smart home, IoT, Queue Management Systems, weather monitoring systems, and flood/landslide warning systems.
- Used machine learning algorithms in IoT applications such as smoke detectors, vehicle accident monitoring systems, and anti-theft systems to prevent theft of solar panels installed in remote weather monitoring stations.

Real Time Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

Patan, Nepal

FIRMWARE SOFTWARE INTERN

Aug. 2016 - Dec. 2016

• Developed a prototype system to detect earthquakes using an off-the-shelf accelerometer. The system was designed to detect P and S waves and act as an earthquake monitoring and early-warning system.

Education

Washington State University (WSU)

Pullman, WA

DOCTOR OF PHILOSOPHY, COMPUTER SCIENCE

August 2018 - May 2023 (expected)

· Research and development of machine learning algorithms and sensor system for mobile health.

Kathmandu University (KU)

Dhulikhel, Nepal

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING IN ELECTRONICS AND COMMUNICATION ENGINEERING

March 2012 - September 2016

- Final Year Project: Comparative Analysis of Routing Protocols for Wireless Body Area Networks.
- Cumulative GPA: 3.89 on a 4.00 scale
- Relevant Coursework: C, C++, Electronics, Numerical Analysis, Calculus

Publications

Adar: Adversarial Activity Recognition in Wearables

Westminister, CO, USA

The 38^{th} IEEE/ACM International Conference on Computer Aided Design (ICCAD)

Nov 4-7, 2019

Adversarial Transferability in Wearable Sensor Systems

ARXIV PREPRINT Mar 2020

Mobile Health for Alcohol Recovery and Relapse Prevention

Washington D.C., USA

The 5^{th} IEEE/ACM International Conference on Connected Health: Applications, Systems and Engineering Technologies

Dec 2020

Stress Classification and Personalization: Getting the most out of the least

Remote

THE 17^{th} IEEE-EMBS International Conference on Wearable and Implantable Body Sensor Networks (BSN'21)

Jun 2021

Associations Between Physiological Signals Captured Using Wearable Sensors and Self-reported Outcomes Among Adults in Alcohol Use Disorder Recovery: Development and Usability Study

JOURNAL OF MEDICAL INTERNET RESEARCH

Jul 2021

NOVEMBER 2, 2021 RAMESH K. SAH · RÉSUMÉ

Virtual

IEEE CONSUMER COMMUNICATIONS & NETWORKING CONFERENCE

Oct 2021

Honors & Awards

| 2019 | Recipient of Graduate and Professional Student Association (GPSA) student travel grant, Washington State |
|------|--|
| 2019 | University |
| 2018 | Awarded full-time RA/TA scholarship, Washington State University |
| 2015 | Recipient of ERASMUS Mundus INTACT student exchange scholarship, Kathmandu University |
| 2016 | Merit Scholarship for Academic Excellence, Kathmandu University |
| 2012 | First Prize in Society of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (SEEE) Circuit Competition, Kathmandu |
| 2012 | University |

Open Source Projects _____

Adar

TENSORFLOW IMPLEMENTATION OF THE PAPER, "ADAR: ADVERSARIAL ACTIVITY RECOGNITION IN WEARABLES"